<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elise Bonnail Projects</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Elise Bonnail Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 17:37:32 +0201</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SteppingOn</title>
      <link>/posts/steppingon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 17:37:32 +0201</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/steppingon/</guid>
      <description>Motivation The goal of this project was to explore to possibility of remotely controlling the actions of users in Virtual Reality without them noticing. I implemented a virtual environment (using Unity3D and the Oculus Quest) that can steer a user’s walking motion towards a specific location in space using subtle rotations of the visual field of view. For this, I adapted and reimplemented HapticRetargeting, a paper from Azmandian et al. published at ACM CHI 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet Locomotion</title>
      <link>/posts/puppet-locomotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 11:18:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/puppet-locomotion/</guid>
      <description>This project consisted in designing, implementing and evaluating a locomotion technique. You can find the starting idea and the motivations of this locomotion technique in the previous post. You can find here the code and the apk.
My idea is to use the metaphor of the puppet. The user can control a puppet with his fingers, and make it evolve in its environment. Not only is the user the puppeteer, he is also the puppet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locomotion Techniques</title>
      <link>/posts/locomotion-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 15:11:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/locomotion-techniques/</guid>
      <description>To be able to take full advantage of the virtual environment in VR, it is necessary to be able to move around, often with a reduced real space. Many means of locomotion in VR have been proposed, such as teleportation or redirected walking. Here are three ideas of locomotion in VR that I thought of.
Roll the wheelchair The idea of this locomotion technique is to imitate the use of a wheelchair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VR roll-a-ball</title>
      <link>/posts/lab3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 08:10:25 +0101</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab3/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this lab was to adapt our roll-a-ball game to VR. We used the Oculus Quest. Here are the steps to remember to create an Oculus application on Unity :
  In Build Settings, switch platform to Android
  In the Asset Store, download and import Oculus Integration
  In Edit &amp;gt; Project Settings &amp;gt; Player &amp;gt; Other settings &amp;gt; Graphic API, remove Vulkan
  In Edit &amp;gt; Project Settings &amp;gt; Player &amp;gt; XR Settings, check &amp;ldquo;Virtual Reality Supported&amp;rdquo; and add Oculus to the VR SDKs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity roll-a-ball</title>
      <link>/posts/lab1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 07:45:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab1/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this lab was to create a roll-a-ball game to learn Unity&amp;rsquo;s basics, inspired from this tutorial :
https://learn.unity.com/project/roll-a-ball?uv=2019.4
We had the possibility to follow another more advanced tutorial, but although I already have a little experience with Unity, I preferred to do the roll-a-ball game to be sure that I had the basics. And I was right, because I learnt some important points.
This is what the resulting game looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Display</title>
      <link>/posts/ultimate-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 15:09:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ultimate-display/</guid>
      <description>The ultimate display would, of course, be a room within which the computer can control the existence of matter. A chair displayed in such aroom would be good enough to sit in. Handcuffs displayed in such a room would be confining, and a bullet displayed in such a room would be fatal. With appropriate programming such a display could literally be the Wonderland into which Alice walked.&amp;mdash; Ivan E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyper Reality</title>
      <link>/posts/hyper-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 13:43:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hyper-reality/</guid>
      <description>Hyper-Reality is a short film created by Keiichi Matsuda. It presents a dystopian and provocative vision of future, where Mixed Reality is used daily. Because of this, advertising is pervasive. Signs are added everywhere. Reality is modified to appear more attractive, like this supermarket which appears more stocked than in reality. The products appear differently depending on who you are, in order to sell more.
Possible scenarios We could imagine a lot of other scenarios in which Mixed Reality technology can create problems for the user or can be abused by content creators, authorities, users or other entities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Setup</title>
      <link>/posts/unitysetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 09:12:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/unitysetup/</guid>
      <description>Here is how to setup Unity environment.
  Download and install Unity Hub following those intructions : https://docs.unity3d.com/Manual/GettingStartedInstallingHub.html
  Open Unity Hub. In the tab &amp;ldquo;Installs&amp;rdquo;, click &amp;ldquo;Add&amp;rdquo; to install the Unity version you need. If you need to develop for Oculus Quest, make sure &amp;ldquo;Android Build Support&amp;rdquo; is checked.
  To create a project, you can then click &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; in the &amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo; tab. Click the arrow next to &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; to create a project with a specific Unity version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Setup</title>
      <link>/posts/blogsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 09:10:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blogsetup/</guid>
      <description>To create this blog I used Hugo, an open source framework to generate static websites. The first step is to install Hugo, following these instructions :
https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/
Then, to create a page, you just need to use this command :
hugo new site [sitename]
Theme Hugo allows you to make beautiful websites easily, thanks to themes organized in git repositories. You can find them here : https://themes.gohugo.io/
Those GitHub repositories usually contain an exampleSite to have a look at the theme, and to see how it is organized.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
