<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Elise Bonnail Projects</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Elise Bonnail Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 08:10:25 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lab 3 : VR roll-a-ball</title>
      <link>/posts/lab3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 08:10:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab3/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this lab was to adapt our roll-a-ball game to VR. We used the Oculus Quest. Here are the steps to remember to create an Oculus application on Unity :
  In Build Settings, switch platform to Android
  In the Asset Store, download and import Oculus Integration
  In Edit &amp;gt; Project Settings &amp;gt; Player &amp;gt; Other settings &amp;gt; Graphic API, remove Vulkan
  In Edit &amp;gt; Project Settings &amp;gt; Player &amp;gt; XR Settings, check &amp;ldquo;Virtual Reality Supported&amp;rdquo; and add Oculus to the VR SDKs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 2 : Unity roll-a-ball</title>
      <link>/posts/lab1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 07:45:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab1/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this lab was to create a roll-a-ball game to learn Unity&amp;rsquo;s basics, inspired from this tutorial :
https://learn.unity.com/project/roll-a-ball?uv=2019.4
We had the possibility to follow another more advanced tutorial, but although I already have a little experience with Unity, I preferred to do the roll-a-ball game to be sure that I had the basics. And I was right, because I learnt some important points.
This is what the resulting game looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Display</title>
      <link>/posts/ultimate-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 15:09:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ultimate-display/</guid>
      <description>The ultimate display would, of course, be a room within which the computer can control the existence of matter. A chair displayed in such aroom would be good enough to sit in. Handcuffs displayed in such a room would be confining, and a bullet displayed in such a room would be fatal. With appropriate programming such a display could literally be the Wonderland into which Alice walked.&amp;mdash; Ivan E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyper Reality</title>
      <link>/posts/hyper-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 13:43:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hyper-reality/</guid>
      <description>Hyper-Reality is a short film created by Keiichi Matsuda. It presents a dystopian and provocative vision of future, where Mixed Reality is used daily. Because of this, advertising is pervasive. Signs are added everywhere. Reality is modified to appear more attractive, like this supermarket which appears more stocked than in reality. The products appear differently depending on who you are, in order to sell more.
Possible scenarios We could imagine a lot of other scenarios in which Mixed Reality technology can create problems for the user or can be abused by content creators, authorities, users or other entities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 11:14:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>some text, maybe italic, maybe bold ?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
